## **PAUL SAENZ**

## FULL STACK WFB DEVELOPER

paulsaenzsucre@outlook.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio

### **SUMMARY**

A full-stack developer with a strong understanding of Ruby on Rails and JavaScript, and 1+ years of experience. I prioritize collaboration, pair programming, and remote work. I developed an app that reduced manual receipt and invoice filling time by 75% (from 2 minutes to 30 seconds) and resolved a significant bottleneck in order taking, increasing customer service efficiency by 35% during rush hour. I am currently seeking a full-stack developer role in a collaborative company.

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3.

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools.

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Full Stack Web Developer

Remote October 2022 – Present

- SPEND TRACKER Is a highly intuitive and dynamic app that enables users to record their expenses. It offers
  data synchronization across multiple devices and password protection.
  - For this project, I utilized Ruby on Rails as the tech stack for both frontend and backend development. PostgreSQL was chosen as the database for its seamless integration with Ruby on Rails, ensuring optimal performance and scalability. GitHub Repository
- SPACE TRAVELERS HUB Is a web application caters to a company offering commercial and scientific space travel services. Users can conveniently book rockets and participate in curated space missions.
   Built with JavaScript, React, and Redux, the application leverages the api.spacexdata.com as the API endpoint for seamless data integration. <u>GitHub Repository</u>
- BOOKSTORE APP Is a user-friendly single-page web app designed for managing book lists. Users can
  effortlessly add, edit, and remove books, including titles and authors.
   The project was developed using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and React, ensuring a seamless and interactive
  experience for users as they efficiently organize their book collections. GitHub Repository
- MATH MAGICIANS Is an intuitive and user-friendly single-page application designed to empower users with
  the ability to perform a wide range of simple calculations effortlessly. With its sleek and straightforward
  interface, the app showcases a robust calculator that caters to all your mathematical needs.
   Built with React and JavaScript, Math Magicians offers a dynamic user experience. GitHub Repository
- LEADERBOARD Is a project that lets users see a list of scores. It also provides the user with a form to add
  his own scores to the list. It uses the Leaderboard API to get and post scores and has an object-oriented
  approach using a model view presenter pattern.
   Harnessing the power of HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript, this project sets the stage for an engaging and

#### PHOENIX SOFTWARE & SYSTEMS E.I.R.L.

user-friendly leaderboard experience. GitHub Repository

Lima, Perú

Developer

January 2022 - March 2022

- Successfully enhanced a custom receipt and e-invoice system for a restaurant owner who was unhappy with the existing solutions in the market.
- Enabled the system to work on a different computer with a limited interface that only allowed waiters to manage dine in orders and connect to the same database as the main application.
- Implemented features that allow the waiters to: manage dine in orders, print receipts for each order, view the

- tables' status and order details for each table.
- Resolved a significant bottleneck in order taking, increasing customer service efficiency by 35% during rush hour, and enabling a 100% increase in delivery order taking.
- Built the project using Visual Basic 6 and Microsoft Access.

#### PHOENIX SOFTWARE & SYSTEMS E.I.R.L.

Lima, Perú

#### Developer

April 2021 - September 2021

- Successfully developed a custom receipt and e-invoice system for a restaurant owner who was unhappy with the existing solutions in the market.
- Implemented features that allow the user to: manage orders, print receipts for each order, choose different order types, view the tables' status and order details for each table.
- Reduced manual receipt and invoice filling time by 75% (from 2 minutes to 30 seconds) and allowed the owner to manage 150+ orders per day.
- Integrated an electronic invoice API service into the application to streamline the process of generating electronic invoices
- Built the project using Visual Basic 6 and Microsoft Access.

## SAENZ & ASOCIADOS AJUSTADORES DE SINIESTROS S.A.C.

Lima, Perú

### Senior Claims Analyst

November 2019 - October 2022

- Successfully resolved over fifty claims, resulting in a 95% customer satisfaction rate.
- Assisted in the training and development of new claims analysts, resulting in a 50% reduction in claims errors and rework.

## AFTER THE STORM AJUSTADORES DE SEGUROS S.A.C.

Lima, Perú

## Senior Claims Analyst

May 2017 - October 2019

- Successfully resolved over fifty claims, resulting in a 95% customer satisfaction rate.
- Assisted in the training and development of new claims analysts, resulting in a 30% reduction in claims errors and rework.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **MICROVERSE**

October 2022 - May 2023

#### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1400+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Led software development projects from inception to completion, ensuring successful delivery and meeting project goals.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

# UNIVERSIDAD INCA GARCILASO DE LA VEGA Business Management, International Business

August 2004 - December 2009

- Successfully earned my Bachelor's Degree in Business Administration and Management, demonstrating a strong foundation in the principles and practices of the field.
- Completed a rigorous curriculum consisting of 220 credits, encompassing a wide range of courses that provided me with a comprehensive understanding of business administration and management.